<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Josh Wulf</title>
    <link>https://joshwulf.com/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Josh Wulf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshwulf.com/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Maybe Pattern using a TypeScript Type Guard</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/typescript-maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/typescript-maybe/</guid>
      <description>You’re sat at a restaurant, and you order a beer. The waiter disappears into the kitchen, and returns a couple of minutes later, empty-handed. “I’m sorry,” he says. “I could not get your beer.”
Now here is the six-million dollar question: is the restaurant out of the beer that you ordered (business logic), or is the restaurant kitchen on fire (infrastructure failure)?
And how do you model those two distinct failure states in your API?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CampJS IX — 2018</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/campjs-ix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/campjs-ix/</guid>
      <description>Classic #campjs pic.twitter.com/TmnmBMF0jG
&amp;mdash; Glen Arrowsmith (@garrows) August 10, 2018  My heartfelt thanks to the organisers and my fellow attendees at @campjs IX. It was a weekend of sleep deprivation of the body, and nourishment of the soul.
&amp;mdash; Josh Wulf (Alt Super Meta) (@sitapati) August 13, 2018  Take me back to #CampJS - a huge thank you to all the organisers; such a thoughtful, inclusive, highly entertaining and fun packed weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript: Return considered harmful</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/return-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/return-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript — the language of the Gods.
return — basically the GOTO statement of 2017_*_
_* T&amp;amp;C apply._
Born in the turbulent crucible of an asynchronous environment, with unpredictable response times and failure rates. For programmers coming from a traditional multi-threaded environment like Java or C#, JavaScript lives in strange and alien world where storms the size of entire planets rage, and lightning bolts pierce the ether.
The classic newbie mistake in JavaScript is to ask: “Why doesn’t this work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Righto — async done right in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/righto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/righto/</guid>
      <description>If you program in server-side JavaScript there is no way that you can avoid dealing with asynchronous functions.
Callbacks, Promises, and async/await are some of the ways that you may have heard of dealing with asynchronous programming in JavaScript. But you may not have heard of Righto — literally the best library of all time for async programming in JS.
Kory Nunn’s Righto library is — according to him — way better than Promises and Async/Await combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is no good coding, only good refactoring</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/no-good-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/no-good-coding/</guid>
      <description>On a standard 101-key keyboard, there are 100 keys that increase technical debt, and only one key that reduces it.
 When you write code you produce functionality and technical debt. Refactoring code is the process of reducing technical debt while preserving functionality.
Yesterday, I spent the afternoon refactoring a method in one of the Magikcraft components.
I refactored it three or four times, extracting and consolidating pieces of logic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>