<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quantum mechanics on Josh Wulf</title>
    <link>https://joshwulf.com/categories/quantum-mechanics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quantum mechanics on Josh Wulf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joshwulf.com/categories/quantum-mechanics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Quantum Computers with Q#</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/programming-in-q#/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/programming-in-q#/</guid>
      <description>This week I’m at the NDC Developer Conference in Sydney. While here, I attended a workshop on programming Quantum computers using Q#, run by John Azariah, the creator of the Q# programming language.
We&amp;#39;re on Task 1.2 of the Q# quantum programming workshop. Linear vector algebra in multi-dimensional complex space... Entanglement and teleportation are coming. pic.twitter.com/wU7LVSeozv
&amp;mdash; Josh Wulf (Alt Super Meta) (@sitapati) September 19, 2018  Q# is a recently released Microsoft language specifically developed for programming quantum computer operations from a classical computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biocentricism: How Life and Consciousness Are the Keys to Understanding the True Nature of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://joshwulf.com/blog/biocentrism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshwulf.com/blog/biocentrism/</guid>
      <description>Today’s classic cut: here’s a book review I wrote in 2014 on Robert Lanza’s “Biocentrism: How Life and Consciousness Are the Keys to Understanding the True Nature of the Universe”. You’re welcome!
After reading a lot on relativity, quantum mechanics, and consciousness, this is the first book where I felt that the author had a solid grasp of all three and was able to bring something to the conversation.
The Western scientific revolution was predicated on an ontology of objective things that had an existence independent of observers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>